all right so what a day keep your energy
levels up we got one last talk super
excited about it so uh yeah so uh my
colleague Scott thank you so much for
jumping in last minute uh to give this
talk um Scott gave this talk at our
local Charlottesville data science
Meetup just a week ago that was its
first version so it's nice to be able to
give the talk again uh and he's going to
be talking about the r in RG so and how
we measure it so really excited to have
Scott share some of the research and
work that he's been doing um and I don't
know what else do you need from your
hype man so that's good enough all right
terrific so uh Scott bring us home all
right
so um I think we've had an earful this
week you know these past two days about
what the problem is um I'm I'm going to
just touch on it briefly just to get the
juices flowing um and then about
measuring it uh and then finally uh how
do we deal with it on the right here I
did a quick search for hey give me some
spectacular fails for for chat gbt and
there there's a nice list of them over
on
medium um so the reason why we do
retrieval log Mana generation is because
uh you know obviously the the llms need
some help they're they're pretty dumb on
their own
um but I if we get if we get the
retrieval part
wrong we're going to get wrong answers
it's going to it's going to spit out
what it's what it's looking at and it's
not going to get get the right answer
and it might not give us the complete
answer that we need and
uh that has you know obviously a bad
effect on uh on the the perception of
how well we're doing for the for the end
user um the also on the right are some
more fails I I like collecting these um
this is this is I mean we've we've seen
several different diagrams this is not
any one particular rag diagram or our
recommended rag diagram but this these
are some of the components that are
common in in rag architecture and the
reason I brought it up is uh uh uh you
know anybody who's built any kind of
system uh of more than two components
realizes that you know the complexity
expands exponentially with every little
arrow going to another box
there we have uh and if you can see
there's little little notepads where
where we're doing logging and little
locks for for where we have access
controls um the reason I have it up here
is uh these are these are spots that
that are the trouble areas I mean
obviously everything else can fail but
these These are these spots in
particular are I think um uh specific to
to to rag
itself um now in general when I'm
talking about uh you know look this is
already a problem everyone recognizes a
problem and and there are some solutions
out there meant to address it uh
traceability um the the some of these
things that I have on the screen now
those products are meant for um really
in instrumenting uh a rag system um the
the problem from my perspective for for
what I need is that these are lagging
metrics I need I need to operate a
little bit earlier in in the stack um
the the other problem with uh tagging
something on on the very end is if
you're in that tight little Loop of
experimentation changing things
measuring it and seeing how things are
doing um you've got to run through all
of your queries again and you've got to
call your LM again to to uh to to come
up with those with those measurements
and that that's slow I think there was a
question earlier today how how do I
speed up the you know the answers that
I'm getting or the the responses that
I'm getting from uh the
llm um and and so if if you're only
looking at it from the outside in um
those those the problems that you see
are are very hard to debug you want to
get in and look at every one of those uh
Junctions and say all right there's a
problem here this this this part of my
stack is is working well
so uh I've I've labeled a couple of
these and hopefully these these you know
you guys get excited about the
particular ones that I've chosen to to
highlight here the these are these are
good ones to sell for us because um uh
just to just to explain so missed the
Box above you know that's not very
that's not very interesting you know
we're missing we don't have content in
our in our uh in our index well get it
in there you know index it and the stuff
that I was talking about later you know
okay we're not really interested in that
but we can we can have a dramatic effect
on this on the r part here that's the
the two red boxes with the arrows there
those are the ones that we can have the
most dramatic effect
on uh and as it turns out uh it's uh
kind of the the limiting factor and the
greatest contribution to quality of the
end result is well the context that
you're that you're giving uh the LM to
work with to begin um there are a couple
of terms up here and and thankfully
everyone in here uh uh came here for the
search aspects of these um just for um
just for uh completeness uh the
definitions of uh that I'll be using for
precision and recall data scientists I
believe use a slightly different uh uh I
mean use these terms in a different
context maybe but this is exactly what I
mean and
uh uh you know we have as as uh
information retrieval uh practitioners
we have processes
um and uh and metrics in place already
to to measure these and and talk about
them in in a a clear way um one of the
problems that we've always had and and
probably we still have for a maybe a few
more months is that um there's always
been this notion of all relevant there
was a question earlier like well how do
we know what what what a relevant
document is um even uh even more
stickier is is that uh when you you look
at some of the um academic uh
documentation about how they how they
evaluate relevance it's um how well this
particular query uh is relevant to every
single document in your Corpus in order
to say whether or not you've returned
every relevant document you have to know
whether or not you've returned every
relevant document and compared it that's
that's
hard so uh you know we we have some
little steps hopefully the little
graphic here is is familiar by now uh
cupid.com uh human human measurements
are still the gold standard uh you know
according to tr according to everybody
according to me uh you know my human
human uh human judgments are uh what
we're aiming for we're we're aiming to
please humans no matter how many
machines stand between us and and the
search engine um that's what we're
shooting for the problem is that uh
getting uh getting someone to sit down
and look at uh every search result for
every query or your top end queries um
that that's expensive it's also
incomplete every every uh every time you
index a new document you're getting new
new stuff in your index um the the the
kinds of queries that you see on your
site there are Trends they come and go
all you you don't have your your data is
not
static it the problem gets even harder
when uh you're dealing in an expert
domain uh when you're dealing with um
well just to be frank documents that you
yourself don't understand so uh um I've
worked on a couple of different systems
where I I personally couldn't judge the
relevance I had no idea whether a
particular legal document um was
answering uh the the information need of
the person asking the question and there
and there are other areas like I'm
certainly not an AI expert either and I
don't know uh if you know this
particular um archive uh paper is going
to be addressing someone's um
convolutional Network query I I really
don't know um and and obviously uh you
know we've we've heard from Moody today
uh I'm not a finance expert I don't know
anything about uh credit ratings or how
they happen so I I can't answer those
questions the people on on your team
they're developers right uh team
collaboration is is more difficult when
you can't uh share that knowledge when
when when even explaining once like this
this document is relevant to this query
because you can do that once but it's a
whole field of knowledge that you'd have
to explain you'd have to create a
paralal on your team in order to
understand all of that
relevance so um you know we we we turn
to to AI to to help us out with this uh
hopefully I can build an AI to take my
job uh I heard uh I think it was two
weeks ago uh Charlie Hall was at uh Sig
in uh in Europe uh and and I heard the
phrase uh aluminium standard instead of
the gold standard so this this would be
artificially generated uh judgments on
on uh query do pairs um so definitely
less expensive uh you know even even
with the most expensive model you have
humans are still more expensive the
human time is still more expensive um
you can have this eventually complete
you know depending on how much you want
to spend on it how quickly you want to
generate these things um you could
probably generate these uh evaluations
as fast as you're indexing new documents
and creating new
queries
um but uh there's there's still a
challenge there in that uh if if you're
not extremely explicit about you uh you
know your guidelines for creating these
evaluations um you can still generate D
LM could still generate uh uh different
different judgments using the exact same
reasoning the same query do pair um I'm
going to give this a three well uh when
I ran it last time you gave it a two and
you said exactly the same uh same uh
justification for it and and lastly uh
you know llms have been trained on the
sum of all human knowledge right
everything published online and uh I
think there's sort of a uh a return to
mean on on intelligence there there you
know it's collected all of the um all
the uh I I won't name any any particular
social site but you know all of those
comments it's collected Wikipedia and
stack Overflow comments right and I
think there's it really doesn't know um
you know which which opinion it should
voice on on any particular thing so um
even though they're kind of smart
they're not they're not an expert they
and they're probably not an expert in
your
data so so let's build let's build an
expert AI um for this purpose
um this is sort of my road map um we'll
start with some human judgments we'll
get uh we'll get some of the experts
that we know understand the queries they
understand the Corpus um and we'll also
get some uh I mean not you know uh kids
down the street but you know some
professionals who uh um at least uh have
can understand the words that are being
said um and we we'll get them to uh to
to judge these these documents
um what we'll do is we'll find um cases
where the expertise shows so it's their
cases where um the human uh let's say
gave it a a one the expert gave it a
zero um we want to find those uh those
slight disagreements and then we'll
we'll ask the El we we'll present the
problem to an El we'll say look in in
your own words you know here's here's an
uh a lay person's Judgment of relevance
um they got it wrong uh the expert said
this was uh this was a zero and not a
one um reason through that in your own
words because uh the reason why I don't
we don't ask experts to do that is
because we it's hard enough to get them
to write down you know sit down and
click a little drop down thing let alone
type out a little
paragraph um and then once we have that
collected for uh for these um hard
negatives uh we'll combine them together
and hopefully um all of this together
the the reasoning that it's come up with
with will will be enough in context to
rate new uh judge new documents um more
like an
expert so uh this this is a description
of of of how we uh how we did that um
the uh the the graph on the right is a
histogram of the the four humans that we
asked to um judge roughly 200 query do
Pairs and the the I'm not going to build
suspense the black line is is uh the llm
uh we called her jez
Judy um and and you'll see that uh Judge
Judy is is kind of um uh unopinionated
about about things uh out sort of out of
the box with a very vanilla prompt um
she's uh kind of optimistic like you
know I can I can see you know why this
might be relevant why it might not be
relevant I'm just I'll go ahead and give
it a
one
um so yeah like I said we we we looked
for areas where the uh the experts
disagreed with the non-experts just just
by one degree um and generated those uh
those explanations using you know a diff
a different prompt uh to generate those
explanations for each one of those
pairs
um and
then something like this so um you know
act as a judge looking at this uh you
know here are here's uh here are the
fields this is what the document looks
like you know all this stuff is going
into the context that uh we're providing
for this sort of metat task this isn't
quite getting down to the point where
we're actually judging documents we're
judging we're building an AI to uh build
another
one um and uh just as sort of a concrete
example on on the left here are
documents that might be uh returned for
a query for Star Wars um uh the the uh
ranking uh that was given by uh the uh
just out of the box AI said you know
what uh episode one that's barely
relevant that that's not relevant to a
Star Wars query that's the that's the
worst one nobody's ever going to want to
see that um and then you know we come in
with a a movie critic uh Ai and say look
um the expert disagreed and gave it a
excuse me uh gave it a
two explain why and and sort of this is
some you know an explanation that you
might get out of that so this this is
what we would put in uh in the the
context as we're going along and judging
new
documents so um with with all of these
uh explanations all of these examples of
disagreement and uh you know in the in
the lm's own words why these
disagreements happened uh we we sampled
those now uh with you know these ever
expanding context you know maybe we
could have just shoved them all in and
and as as the uh uh the learning
parameters or the context for judging
new things but uh my my intuition well
this this was mon months ago my
intuition was we need to find a small
set of you know handful of examples that
will actually uh I guess get the uh get
get the llm talking like an expert not
not thinking like an expert um and and
so uh you know I I have all of these uh
all of these examples out I used uh
basian
optimization um to uh to optimize Coen
Kappa Coen Kappa is just how much do two
um two Raiders agree with each other uh
uh discounting um the chance that they
might just agree by by chance
so we had three uh three uh three
categories for judgment you know
normalizing for uh the odds that uh you
know that one agreed you know put it two
just by random chance in the other one
uh and the coin Capa by the way is is a
measure from negative one to one so a
negative one would be perfect uh
disagreement you know I never agree with
that person uh one would be perfect
agreement and zero would be just a
random
um um so we pick we pick this this basy
and optimization process is pick pick a
few uh pick a few of these examples
yes it actually did so you remember the
the histogram with the the the experts
and the non-experts we were able to
migrate um the the judgments that the LM
was coming up with those were more in
agreement with an expert than with the
the non-experts uh and in fact um I
narrowed it down to a specific expert
and could get uh could get my agreement
more in line with that expert than with
than those two experts agreed with each
other
um and so the benefit that we're getting
out of this is that when we say when we
go back and look at precision and and
recall when we ask about you know did I
get relevant documents in my context uh
we can have more confidence about yeah
an expert's going to look at that
context and say yes these These are uh I
would judge these documents uh like you
have already uh actually getting the uh
the right documents there is is a
separate process but the documents
you're showing me right now I agree with
how they're
judged um and the the the testing that
we do uh it's cheaper faster it's it's
mostly offline um the judgments uh can
be cashed we we saw uh uh presentation
earlier they was talking about caching
some of these uh more expensive things
we only need to look at a a query do
pair once uh in in a particular example
um if we do something like uh
adjust our chunk size or change uh the
llm that we're pointing to or you know
some other things we might need to do
refresh the the whole cache but in
general we can iterate faster with with
uh with all these
metrics um but but I mean the most
important part is at the very end the
person with the with the uh the
telescope looking outside in um at how
we're generating things those metrics
are are better those metric you know we
got positive it's actually a separate
group
um we got positive feedback their their
evaluation of the job that we're doing
was better and um obviously the the end
goal is to get happier
customers
um so just to just to summarize uh the
the whole point of this um better cont
better uh in context uh results that we
give the end llm when we're when we're
generating our our our response to human
we give it better context it's going to
generate better text right improving
that context means that we have to have
good judgments we have to have
confidence in our judgment um we're
going to tweak things we're going to get
uh possibly irrelevant things we need to
know about that as we're
experimenting if we're if we're careful
if if we uh spend some time we can get
uh an llm to judge uh better than
off-the-shelf uh you know stock uh stock
l them and judge documents more like an
expert would judge
them um and then you know obviously all
this is so that we can uh try new things
at the retrieval side um slightly adjust
our recency boost you know whatever that
is to get better documents at the top
the the the uh image I have on the right
hand side here is that we would uh Eric
would AB desperately love to get Judy
into into Cupid uh part if if you've
worked with Cupid one of the um things
you'll see when uh you you change the
the boost on something you get new
documents or you index new things and
you have don't have ratings you'll see a
little frog there and we have a little
frog pond report that says how many how
many documents are being returned by
your queries that don't have ratings and
you know the idea is you go in and you
you try to eliminate all the frogs well
um this this uh pull request will give
you the ability to go ahead and say uh
you know what let's let let's go ahead
and let Judge Judy go in and uh fill in
the the Frog Pond
forming uh thank you I guess uh we're
doing Q QR codes so this presentation is
at that at that QR code also osc's
hiring um and and and the last thing
that last point I want to make just on
on the uh on The Talk itself is that um
in h side conversations actually there's
in a question last week but it's come up
again is that you know I did this
experiment with a particular expert in
mind um the the question I got at the
time was well what con what constitutes
expertise you know who is the expert why
why do they get to judge um and and uh
my answer at the time was that well it's
uh you know that person has uh they've
been hired for that role they were hired
for that knowledge the the end end users
the people who subscribe to that service
they uh they are going to that site for
that expert for that person's expertise
um so in that case it was pretty clear
but uh in general you know you say the
word expert but it could be you know I I
happen to be recently an expert in uh
uh uh automobile troubles that you might
encounter with a a late model Jetta
caused by a 16-year-old
driver uh you know that's my reluctant
area of expertise right now um but you
know so when you're looking at maybe
fashion you know you might find someone
who's uh a shoe offici in AO or
something like that uh we we were
talking about doing routing you can
probably pick and choose the kinds of uh
kinds of Doc kinds of query doc pairs
that you're judging and and tailor your
your prompt to uh a different kind of
expert for th for those uh uh
circumstances anyway I just wanted to
drop that last part in uh thank
you all right let me go am I
on yep okay uh let me go ahead and uh
got a online question so was this done
with the intention to automate the
Judgment process absolutely yep and then
quick followon question could you be
using this for training an LTR
model
yes yeah I guess my my my my thought on
that one
is if you're measurement tool is also
your optimization tool you may be very
success
without actually being successful right
yeah absolutely and and there's there's
another thing that came up uh in a paper
uh I guess towards the beginning of the
year where uh when when an llm is asked
to evaluate the uh the text that was
generated by another LM it is very uh
gushing in its in its uh approval of of
how it's written so uh there's there's
definitely some danger about uh having a
feedback loop or you know feedback look
between those two
things
can yeah yeah can you um help clarify
the intuition around the use of the
non-expert with the expert comparison
because it seems to me that if you have
expert
judgment then you would use that as the
training data and nonexpert is better
than random so what is the non-expert
Judgment get giving you is it because
yeah can you elaborate on that in from
an intuition standpoint absolutely um uh
so I'll I'll just say that I I did not
do it without I I haven't tried it
without the I I came at this approach
with the idea that I'm going to do both
uh in experts and experts I haven't um
tried to do it without the non-experts
but the reason why I I came uh came at
it this way is that what I believe is
important to this process is the
explanation of
why the uh the non-expert and expert
disagree I could ask uh I could ask the
experts I could ask an LM to uh write a
an explanation for um for the Judgment
but I think you run into the same danger
of the explanation is going to be Beyond
me I could ask a paralal why a certain
why these two things are are uh uh
inequal or or not not responsive to each
other but I'm not going to understand
understand it unless I have someone in
between us dumb it down for me does that
does that make
sense isn't that just saying that your
non expert is eliminating the false
positives and the false
negatives confus yeah kind of yeah um I
I also did not try to do anything beyond
the hard negatives um I think that and I
also had a very small window so there
are lots of other things that I can
start trying like expanding the number
of examples that I have expanding the
kinds of examples that I have I I might
even ask it to uh with without the
contrastive explanation I might ask uh
you know maybe if I did have a few of
examples of an expert giving an expert
uh reasoning um that that might even
approve it more just just to clarify on
this question um the judge you had just
a numeric judgment you didn't have a
Verbatim comment on why they rated
that's right so the part of the process
if I understand it correctly is that
when you had those judgments where there
was large disagreement your prompt to
the llm was to tell it to explain what
the difference was yeah on what basis
was it doing that was it based just on a
comparison of the content or like how
how how would it even know to determine
that for a given query document pair um
it's the same document one was rated a
one one was rated a three how can it
even reason on that right so both both
were given the the um the Judgment in uh
instructions the the manual that we gave
to um our humans this is how you this is
how you grade IR relevance on on these
on these pairs um as as sort of um
instruction for this for that particular
task I said um I I tried to make it very
clear that we had a non-expert give this
uh query do pair a a Judgment of one and
however the expert gave it a judgment of
zero explain in you know why this
is yeah uh this is a really encouraging
and enlightening talk I had a question
about how you reintegrate these um
basically you kind of alluded to you you
had a thought of okay well now I've I've
got this explanation from the llm for
the difference uh you you mentioned
maybe you integrate it in the prompt are
you actually retraining SL fine-tuning
this model I guess or how are you
integrating that no no these these are
just uh more in context examples I guess
uh um you know for the for the job of
creating these
judgments uh at the end of this I had a
set of four um four examples of when the
expert disagreed with the non-expert by
just one and the explanation was clear
enough to then let the llm judge the
rest of um my my uh query doc pairs like
an expert oh so just for that just for
that term or query basally okay thank
you I've got a online question um from
Alexandra does it make
sense to do majority vote between
different llm models
yeah and and I think that that even uh
ties
into uh you know that that other part
about having different flavors of of
experts like um you know certainly we
would want to um reud or or look at
things again if we change the underlying
model I mean honestly if we get
agreement with an expert um I think
that's that's good enough right that's
that's as far as we need to go we don't
need some people might aim for
superhuman uh grading but really what
we're aiming for is agreement with with
the experts um and and maybe we can get
that that agreement score that uh you
know Coen Capa even higher um there
there are other uh agreement measures
for for multiple Raiders um we could
have different kinds of Judges saying
look you know I happen to be a
structured Finance expert I happen to be
a um I I don't even know any kind other
kinds of Finance to even come up with
examples but uh I you know I'm I'm a
patent lawyer I'm a intellectual
property lawyer I'm a defense lawyer
whatever let's look at this and see if
we all agree and maybe we have another
one that's like
a a resolver that says you know what
this question looks like uh it would be
best resolved by uh this particular
judge Ensemble uh an ensemble model sort
of all right terrific uh can we get a
round of applause for Scott thank you
for pitching in
[Applause]
um e